What is Data Science?
Data science, also known as data-driven science, is an interdisciplinary field about scientific methods, processes, and systems to extract knowledge or insights from data in various forms.

Standard Lifecycle of Data Science Projects
Data Science Project lifecycle has 6 steps 
1   Business Understanding
2   Data Understanding
3   Data Preparation
4   Modelling
5   Evaluation
6   Deployment

Python Eco System for Data Science
Python's popularity for data science is largely due to the strength of its core libraries 
1. NumPy		2. SciPy 	3. Pandas
4. Matplotlib	5. Seaborn
	
Best Book: Doing Data Science
Authors: Cathy O'Neil, Rachel Schutt

What is Machine Learning?
Machine Learning is a type of Artificial Intelligence that provides the computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed.
OR
Machine learning is when machine learns to program itself! 

Different machine learning techniques
Machine learning uses two types of techniques: 
1. Supervised Learning
Which trains a model on known input and output data so that it can predict future outputs. 
It is basically classified into the following two types:
a. Classification
b. Regression

2. Unsupervised Learning
Group and interpret data based only on input data.
a. Clustering
b. Principal Component Analysis

Applications Of Machine Learning
1. Social Media	2. Search Engines
3. Health Care	4. Banking & Finance
5. Legal Services	6. Retail
7. Public Services	8. Security

Top 5 Machine Learning Libraries
1. TensorFlow	2. Scikit -Learn (SKLearn)
3. Keras		4 NLTK 	5. PyTorch

Machine Learning Mastery with PYTHON==> Jason Brownlee
Introduction to Machine Learning with Python==>Andreas C. Müller & Sarah Guido

What is Deep Learning?
Deep learning is a machine learning technique that teaches computers to do what comes naturally to humans.
OR
Deep learning is a subset of machine learning in Artificial Intelligence. 

TOP 5 Deep Learning Frameworks:
1 Theano	2 TensorFlow	3 Lasagne
4 Keras 	5 MXNet

Deep Learning with Python==>Nikhil Ketkar
Deep Learning with Python==>Francois Chollet

Artificial Intelligence
AI makes it possible for machines to learn from experience.
OR
AI is the simulation of human intelligence by machines.

Applications of AI
1. Gaming
2. Natural Language Processing and translation
3. Expert Systems	4. Vision Systems
5. Speech Recognition
6. Handwriting Recognition
7. Intelligent Robots
8. Data mining, Web Crawler
9. Vision, Virtual Reality

AI A Modern Approach ==> Peter Norvig and Stuart J. Russell

What is IoT?
A network of internet-connected objects able to collect and exchange data using embedded sensors.

IoT Companies
Google, Amazon,  AT&T, Cisco, IBM, Honeywell, Microsoft, Apple, Android etc............
  
IoT Areas:
1. Smart Health	2. Smart Living
3. Smart Industry	4. Animal Tracking
5. Smart Agriculture	6. Smart Homes
7. Smart Transport 	8. Smart Energy 
8. Smart Cities	

Raspberry Pi: (From Python)
It is a credit-card-sized computer that plugs into your TV and a keyboard. It is a capable little computer which can be used in electronics projects.

Best Book for: IoT-with-python==>Gaston-c-hillar
