Debugging in PYCHARM:
It is the process of identifying and fixing problems in Code. The following short-cut keys are required to debug..!!

1 Step Over (F8)
2 Step Into (F7)
3 Force Step Into (Alt+Shift+F7)
4 Step Out (Shift+F8)
5 Run to Cursor (Alt+F9)

Example:
a=int(input("Enter Any Number: "))
b=int(input("Enter Any Number: "))
c=a+b
print("The Result is: ",c)
d=a-b
print("The Result is: ",d)
e=a*b
print("The Result is: ",e)
f=a/b
print("The Result is: ",f)


What is Anaconda?
The Most Popular Python Data Science Platform.
It is a freemium open source distribution of the Python and R PLs for large-scale data processing, predictive analytics and scientific computing. 

How to Install Anaconda?
1. https://www.anaconda.com/download/
2. Click on Python 3.7 version 64-Bit Installer download
3. After successful Installation of Anaconda Platform
4. Go to MSDOS Command Prompt type spyder or jupyter notebook 
5. SPYDER(Scientific PYthon Development EnviRonment) 
6. JUPYteR (formerly==>iPython(JUlia, PYthon and R)

Coding Environments
Anaconda comes with two popular IDEs :

Spyder:
It is a powerful IDE for the Python language with advanced editing, interactive testing, debugging features..!!

General features:
1. iPython=>Enhanced interactive Python interpreter
2. NumPy =>Nummerical PYthon-Linear Algebra 
3. SciPy=>Scientific Python-Signal & Image Processing 
4. Matplotlib=>Interactive 2D/3D plotting
5. Pandas=>For Data Analysis with Data Frames
6. Scikit-learn==> It is a Machine Learning library

Main Components in Spyder.
1 Dashboard	2 Project Explorer
3 Editor		4 Console		5 Help

What is Anaconda Navigator?
It is a desktop GUI, that allows you to launch applications and easily manage conda packages without using command-line commands.

Jupyter Notebook:(http://jupyter.org/) 
Formerly known as the IPython Notebook. It is a server-client application that allows editing and running notebook documents via a web browser. 

Features of Jupyter Notebook:
1 Edit/Run code in the browser
2 It supports 40+ Programming Languages
3 Share notebooks: using email, Dropbox, GitHub
4 BigData Integration